Finding Aid for Jeffrey R. Parsons papers, 1960-2013
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Jeffrey R. Parsons papers 1960-2013 1966-1992
Parsons, Jeffrey R. 1939-
2012180 Aa2
Jeffrey R. Parsons was Curator of Latin American Archaeology and Director of the Museum of Anthropology at the University of Michigan. He was a professor at the same institution for over forty years starting in 1966 and carried out extensive research on settlement patterns in the basin of Mexico, in Peru, and in many other countries. Parsons is known for his role in the development of systematic settlement survey methods in archaeology, a methodology which has become common in archaeological work around the world. Material includes papers, maps, site surveys, photo negatives, aerial photographs and digital scans of the negatives.
70 linear feet in 59 boxes
1 oversize folders
38.5 GB
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The papers (donor no. 10754 ) were received in 2012. A second accession received in 2013.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Jeffrey R. Parsons was born in Washington, D.C., in October 9, 1939. During his childhood, he and his family moved to Philadelphia for a period of five years and afterwards settled in Fairfax, Virginia. He would return as an undergraduate student to Pennsylvania to study geology at the Pennsylvania State University. It was in choosing elective courses that Parsons was introduced to archaeology and anthropology. His interest in those disciplines led him to pursue a graduate education in anthropology. After applying and being accepted to the University of Arizona and the University of Michigan, Parsons chose the program in Michigan where James B. Griffin offered an assistantship at the Museum of Anthropology.
Parsons completed his undergraduate degree in geology and mineralogy in 1961. That summer, and the years to follow, provided a time for him to acquire fieldwork experience through several projects with the Pennsylvania State University. Parsons worked as a field assistant with William Sanders' Teotihuacan Valley Project in Mexico from 1961 to 1966. In 1966, he also worked during a three month period with the Tikal Sustaining Area Project in Guatemala.
The implementation of systematic settlement pattern survey methodology in the Teotihuacan Valley Project played a significant role in the development of archaeology. The use of this methodology reflected a shift in the field of archaeology to a focus on anthropological and cultural issues. Parsons participated in the implementation of this methodology as well as in developing regional surveying for the project. This methodology involved the use of regional surveying of settlement remains to study and find patterns of occupation. This would become standard methodology within the field.
Meanwhile, Parsons was completing his graduate studies in Anthropology while also working as a radiocarbon dating clerk at the Museum of Anthropology. Such experience allowed him to become familiar with ongoing archaeological research around the world. By the end of his Ph.D. studies in 1966, Parsons had started teaching as an assistant professor, as a result of his growing expertise in Mesoamerican archaeology and the University's need for an archaeologist specializing in Latin America. That same year, he also became Curator of Latin American Archaeology at the Museum of Anthropology.
In the following years Parsons developed systematic settlement pattern surveys throughout the Basin of Mexico building on the Teotihuacan Valley Project. The successive site surveys included the Texcoco region in 1967 in the eastern part of the Basin, the areas of Chalco and Xochimilco in the southern Basin in 1969 and 1972, and the northern Basin, specifically the Zumpango area in 1973. Parsons intended for surveys to be an initial stage to further intensive research of the sites. Later research by a number of colleagues and students in the following decades focused their archaeological research on some areas covered by these initial surveys.
Parsons' archaeological research took him to Peru and Argentina for work on settlement patterns. During the late 1970s he participated in several field studies, sponsored by the University of Michigan in the U.S., specifically in New Mexico, Kentucky, and Alabama. The following decade, Parsons carried out ethno-archaeological research in Mezquital, Nexquipayac, and Chimalhuacan, Mexico looking at the use of maguey, salt-making, and insect collection. Other research projects have taken Parsons to Iceland, Egypt, Australia, Mongolia, and Italy. Most of these projects were funded by the National Science Foundation, while a smaller number by the University of Michigan, and the National Geographic Society.
Parson's teaching and administrative experience also expanded beyond the University of Michigan. He went on to become associate professor, later professor of Anthropology, and Director of the Museum of Anthropology at the University of Michigan before also working as a visiting professor in various Latin American countries, mainly during the 1990s. He was invited as professor to the National Autonomous University in Mexico, to the University of Buenos Aires in Argentina, to the National Universities of Tucumán and Catamarca, both in Argentina, as well as to the Higher University of San Andrés in Bolivia. At the University of Michigan, Parsons also became involved with the program in Latin American and Caribbean Studies as Acting and Interim Director for brief one year periods in 1991 and 2001.
In 1968 Parsons married Mary Hrones, a fellow archaeologist whom he had met at the graduate program in Michigan. Hrones and Parsons had worked together in several of the Mexico Basin survey projects and would collaborate again in their research on Peru and other countries in later years. They had one daughter, Apphia, in 1975.
Parsons' achievements in archaeology, teaching, and research have been recognized by his colleagues and several institutions. He was awarded the American Anthropological Association's Alfred V. Kidder Award for lifetime achievement in 1998. In 2002 the University of Michigan, awarded him the Distinguished Faculty Achievement Award. More recently, in 2005, colleagues published Settlement, Subsistence, and Social Complexity: Essays Honoring the Legacy of Jeffrey R. Parsons.
-------------------------
Sources Consulted:
Curriculum Vitae
Nichols, Deborah, "Archaeology on Foot: Jeffrey Parsons and the University of Michigan." in Retrospectives: Works and Lives of Michigan Anthropologists edited by Derek Pomeroy Brereton, 106-135. (Ann Arbor, MI: Dept. of Anthropology, University of Michigan, 2006).
The Jeffrey R. Parsons papers document the archaeologist's research in the Basin of Mexico, his work at the University of Michigan as professor, Curator of Latin American Archaeology, and Director of the Museum of Anthropology, and his work with colleagues and institutions around the world. Materials date from 1960 to 2009 while the bulk of it is from 1966 to 1973. The majority is related to his fieldwork in the Valley of Mexico and includes paper, photographic material, maps, and documentation about materials collected as part of the surveys, such as information on ceramic sherds. The collection is arranged in nine series: Personal Files, Correspondence 1966-2005, Archaeological Sites and Projects, Topical Files, Publications, Student Years, Visual Materials Series, and Maps.
Subjects:
Blanton, Richard E.; Parsons, Jeffrey R.; Parsons, Mary Hrones.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Anthropology.; University of Michigan. Museum of Anthropology.; Anthropology--History.; Anthropology--Study and teaching.; Archaeology.; Basins (Geology)--Mexico.; Land settlement patterns.; Pottery--Analyses.; Mexico, Valley of (Mexico); Oztoticpac (Texcoco de Mora, Mexico); Teotihuacán Valley (Mexico)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Parsons, Jeffrey R.; Anthropology--Mexico.; Archaeology.; Basins (Geology)--Mexico.; Land settlement patterns.; Mexico, Valley of (Mexico); Teotihuacán Valley (Mexico)
Genre Terms:
Aerial photographs.; DVDs.; Negatives.; Photographs.
- Personal Files
  The Personal Files (0.2 linear feet) series holds Jeffrey Parsons curriculum vitae, additional biographical material and a book edited by him about his family's farm in Maine.
  - Biographical Material (Box 1)
  - Life on the Farm and in the Village South Paris, Maine, 2009 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1966-2005
  Parsons carried on an extensive correspondence beginning in his student days and extending throughout his career. Correspondents include many of the leading figures in archeological field work and document his own research as well as his professional activities. The correspondence series is organized into two alphabetically arranged subseries for the years 1966-1990 (acquired directly from Parsons) and 1990-2005 (received through the Museum of Anthropology).
  - 1966-1990
    The subseries Correspondence, 1966-1990 (4.75 linear feet), the first of two correspondence files, includes Parsons' incoming and outgoing correspondence during the first decades of his professional career. The time period for the materials starts in the late 1960s while Parsons was completing his Ph.D. at the same time as teaching at the University of Michigan and doing field research in the Basin of Mexico. It goes on to document Parsons' field work in other regions in Mexico, Peru, and Iceland as well as his work with the University of Michigan Museum of Anthropology and as a professor in Peru, Mexico, and Michigan.
    The subseries is comprised mostly of letters, telegrams, research proposal materials, some postcards and greeting cards among other formats. Materials include correspondence related to his courses, research publications, and professional associations. Correspondence includes communications with mentors, students, fellow archaeologists and anthropologists, renowned figures in the field, the University of Michigan Museum of Anthropology, the College of Literature, Science and Arts, international collaborators and institutions. Some correspondents include: Elizabeth Brumfield, Terence D'Altroy, Larry Gorenflo, James B. Griffin, Charles Hastings, Mary Hodge, Darell LaLone, Ramiro Matos Mendieta, Thomas McGovern, Elinor Melville, Timothy Earle, Deborah Nichols, Lorenzo Roselló Truel, Norbert Ptusy, William T. Sanders, and Mari Carmen Serra.
    Materials for the subseries were received directly from Parsons. Among these, two distinct groupings are discernible. This is reflected in the arrangement where sometimes two or more folders for the same letter will be present. Materials are arranged alphabetically and include miscellaneous folders by letter as well as named folders for frequent correspondents.
    - A 1968-1975 (Box 1)
    - A 1981-1986 (Box 1)
    - A 1986-1989 (Box 1)
    - Academic Press 1976-1983 (Box 1)
    - Alden, John 1977-1983 (Box 1)
    - American Anthropological Association-AD Nominations 1992-1993 (Box 1)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science 1981-1989 (Box 1)
    - Armillas, Pedro 1967-1982 (Box 1)
    - B 1966-1988 (Box 1)
    - B 1980-1989 (Box 1)
    - Bauer, Brian 1983-1989 (Box 1)
    - Bell, Karen 1970-1988 (Box 1)
    - Berdan, Frances F. 1981-1983 (Box 1)
    - Bermann, Marc 1982-1989 (Box 1)
    - Bernard, H. Russell 1983-1989 (Box 1)
    - Bettarel, Robert 1968-1978 (Box 1)
    - Blake, Mike 1981-1989 (Box 1)
    - Blanton, Richard E. 1969-1989 (Box 1)
    - Brodkey, Dale 1971-1977 (Box 1)
    - Browman, David 1973-1979 (Box 1)
    - Brumfiel, Elizabeth 1971-1989 (Box 1)
    - C 1966-1981 (Box 1)
    - C 1974-1987 (Box 1)
    - Charlton, Tom 1968-1988 (Box 1)
    - Cleland, Charles E. 1966-1976 (Box 1)
    - Corona, Eduardo 1980-1985 (Box 1)
    - Cowgill, George 1974-1988 (Box 1)
    - D 1967-1983 (Box 1)
    - D 1980-1987 (Box 2)
    - D'Altroy, Terence (Box 2)
    - de Montmollin, Olivier 1983-1989 (Box 2)
    - Draft Board 1967-1971 (Box 2)
    - Drennan, Robert D. 1980-1986 (Box 2)
    - E 1968-1979 (Box 2)
    - E 1983-1989 (Box 2)
    - Earle, Timothy K. 1971-1989 (Box 2)
    - Escuela Nacional de Antropología e Historia (ENAH) 1986-1987 (Box 2)
    - Evans, Clifford 1970-1978 (Box 2)
    - Evans, Susan 1978-1989 (Box 2)
    - F 1966-1979 (Box 2)
    - F 1973-1987 (Box 2)
    - Farrington, Ian S. 1980-1984 (Box 2)
    - Feinman, Gary M. 1984-1987 (Box 2)
    - Fish, Susan 1984-1989 (Box 2)
    - Ford, Anabel 1980-1983 (Box 2)
    - Ford, Richard I. 1972-1979 (Box 2)
    - Fulbright-Council for the International Exchange of Scholars 1985-1997 (Box 2)
    - Fung Pineda, Rosa 1973-1980 (Box 2)
    - G 1966-1979 (Box 2)
    - G 1980-1986 (Box 2)
    - Gandara, Manuel 1982-1987 (Box 2)
    - García Mora, Juan Carlos 1980-1983 (Box 2)
    - Goland, Carol 1986-1988 (Box 2)
    - Gorenflo, Larry J. 1980-1988 (Box 2)
    - Gregg, Susan A. 1982-1987 (Box 2)
    - Griffin, James B. 1969-1975 (Box 2)
    - Guillén, Sonia 1976-1986 (Box 2)
    - H 1967-1979 (Box 2)
    - H 1980-1989 (Box 2)
    - Harvey, Herbert 1971-1987 (Box 2)
    - Hart, Elizabeth 1977-1983 (Box 2)
    - Hastings, Charles M. 1972-1989 (Box 2)
    - Hastorf, Christine 1980-1988 (Box 2)
    - Haverstock, Dawn 1987-1988 (Box 2)
    - Healan, Dan M. 1979-1985 (Box 2)
    - Hernández, Benito 1968-1983 (Box 2)
    - Hirth, Kenneth 1972-1987 (Box 2)
    - Hispanic American Historical Review 1976-1990 (Box 2)
    - Hodge, Mary 1979-1989 (Box 2)
    - Hole, Frank 1974 (Box 2)
    - Hutterer, Karl 1975-1983 (Box 2)
    - I 1969-1979 (Box 2)
    - I 1974-1989 (Box 2)
    - Iceland 1984-1985 (Box 2)
    - Institute of Andean Studies 1979-1989 (Box 2)
    - Instituto Nacional de Antropología e Historia (INAH) 1966-1979 (Box 3)
    - Instituto Nacional de Antropología e Historia (INAH) 1980-1988 (Box 3)
    - Isbell, William H. 1968-1978 (Box 3)
    - J 1968-1977 (Box 3)
    - J,1981-1989 (Box 3)
    - James, Nicholas 1980-1985 (Box 3)
    - Johnson, Laura 1986-1989 (Box 3)
    - Junker, Laura Lee 1987 (Box 3)
    - K 1968-1979 (Box 3)
    - K 1982-1988 (Box 3)
    - Keatinge, Richard 1978-1985 (Box 3)
    - Kintigh, Keith 1974-1988 (Box 3)
    - Kolata, Alan L. 1982-1989 (Box 3)
    - Kolb, Charles C. 1968-1988 (Box 3)
    - Kowaleski, Stephen A. 1980-1989 (Box 3)
    - L 1967-1979 (Box 3)
    - L 1982-1993 (Box 3)
    - LaLone, Darrell 1969-1982 (Box 3)
    - Latin America Research Review 1973-1977 (Box 3)
    - Lechtman, Heather 1974-1979 (Box 3)
    - Lorandi, Ana Maria 1971-1975 (Box 3)
    - Lynch, Thomas 1968-1977 (Box 3)
    - M 1968-1979 (Box 3)
    - M 1980-1989 (Box 3)
    - M,1985-1989 (Box 3)
    - Mason, Roger 1977-1978 (Box 3)
    - Matos Mendieta, Ramiro 1970-1987 (Box 3)
    - McCullough, John R. 1968-1972 (Box 3)
    - McGovern, Thomas H. 1984-1992 (Box 3)
    - Meggers, Betty J. 1984-1992 (Box 3)
    - Midwest Conference on Andean and Amazonian Archaeology 1976-1987 (Box 3)
    - Midwest Mesoamerican Conference 1978-1989 (Box 3)
    - Millon, René 1967-1974 (Box 3)
    - Melville, Elinor 1973-1989 (Box 3)
    - Mexican Airphoto 1968-1971 (Box 3)
    - Mexican Studies 1983-1984 (Box 3)
    - Monroe, Donna 1973-1976 (Box 3)
    - Moore, Charlotte B. 1974 (Box 3)
    - Morris, Craig 1970-1978 (Box 3)
    - Moseley, Michael E. 1968-1975 (Box 3)
    - Mountjoy, Joseph B. 1972-1975 (Box 3)
    - Muller, Jon 1978 (Box 3)
    - Murra, John V. 1967-1977 (Box 3)
    - Museum of Art 1980 (Box 3)
    - Mutal, Sylvio 1978-1979 (Box 3)
    - Myers, Thomas P. 1973-1976 (Box 3)
    - N 1968-1978 (Box 4)
    - N 1971-1989 (Box 4)
    - National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) 1970-1972 (Box 4)
    - National Science Foundation 1968-1979 (Box 4)
    - New Mexico Press 1981-1989 (Box 4)
    - Nichols, Deborah 1977-1989 (Box 4)
    - Nishimura, Masao 1984-1999 (Box 4)
    - Norr, Lynette 1977-1978 (Box 4)
    - O 1969-1979 (Box 4)
    - O 1980-1989 (Box 4)
    - Offner, Jerome A. 1978-1979 (Box 4)
    - Olafsson, Gudmundur 1984-1989 (Box 4)
    - Olsson, Ingrid U. 1971-1973 (Box 4)
    - Otomi-Miscellaneous 1983-1984 (Box 4)
    - Overall, Clémence 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    - P 1967-1985 (Box 4)
    - P 1967-1978 (Box 4)
    - Palerm, Mrs. A (Carmen Viqueira) 1990 (Box 4)
    - Palsson, Gísli 1984-1988 (Box 4)
    - Parsons, Jeffrey R.-Sabbatical Leave 1977-1991 (Box 4)
    - Parsons, Jeffrey R.-Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (UNAM) documentation 1986-1989 (Box 4)
    - Pinson, Ann 1987 (Box 4)
    - Pires-Ferreira, Edgardo-1972-1978 (Box 4)
    - Popper, Virginia 1980-1989 (Box 4)
    - Pozorski, Thomas and Sheila 1982-1984 (Box 4)
    - Psuty, Norbert 1968-1977 (Box 4)
    - Puleston, Dennis and Olga 1965-1978 (Box 4)
    - Q 1965 (Box 4)
    - R 1969-1979 (Box 4)
    - R 1980-1996 (Box 4)
    - Rackham Subvention 1980 (Box 4)
    - Rambo, Terry 1983-1988 (Box 4)
    - Ramirez, Juan 1978-1984 (Box 4)
    - Ratray, Evelyn 1980-1989 (Box 4)
    - Ribeiro, Marco A. (Tony) 1983-1989 (Box 4)
    - Rick, John 1973-1986 (Box 4)
    - Roselló Truel, Lorenzo 1966-1988 (Box 4)
    - Rowe, John H. 1976-1978 (Box 4)
    - Rudecoff, Christine A. 1975-1985 (Box 4)
    - S 1968-1979 (Box 4)
    - S 1971-1990 (Box 4)
    - S 1981-1987 (Box 4)
    - Sanders, William T. 1967-1979 (Box 4)
    - Sanders, William T. 1984-1990 (Box 4)
    - Santley, Robert 1977-1979 (Box 4)
    - Santley, Robert 1980-1987 (Box 4)
    - Science 1968-1973 (Box 4)
    - Schorger, William D. 1968-1969 (Box 4)
    - Schreiber, Kathy 1982-1988 (Box 4)
    - Schreeuder, Yda 1972-1976 (Box 4)
    - Serra, Mari Carmen 1985-1987 (Box 4)
    - Service, Elman R. 1969-1975 (Box 4)
    - Shiffer, Michael B. 1982-1987 (Box 4)
    - Siemens, Alfred H. 1983-1988 (Box 4)
    - Silva, Jorge 1985-1989 (Box 4)
    - Silverblatt, Irene 1979-1984 (Box 4)
    - Sinopoli, Carla 1984-1989 (Box 4)
    - Slayton, Paul 1983-1986 (Box 4)
    - Smith, Kevin 1983-1989 (Box 5)
    - Smith, Kevin 1990-1996 (Box 5)
    - Smith, Michael E. 1976-1989 (Box 5)
    - Smith, Richard T. 1968-1977 (Box 5)
    - Spath, Carl 1969-1978 (Box 5)
    - Spence, Michael 1967-1978 (Box 5)
    - Spencer, Charles 1979-1987 (Box 5)
    - Speth, John 1973-1989 (Box 5)
    - Stark, Barbara L. 1973-1979 (Box 5)
    - Steiner, Peter 1982-1989 (Box 5)
    - Stocker, Terrance 1982-1989 (Box 5)
    - T 1967-1981 (Box 5)
    - T 1980-1988 (Box 5)
    - Taft, Mary 1981-1986 (Box 5)
    - Tolstoy, Paul 1971-1985 (Box 5)
    - Tolstoy, Paul 1978 (Box 5)
    - Trombold, Charles D. 1984-1989 (Box 5)
    - U 1970-1994 (Box 5)
    - V 1970-1984 (Box 5)
    - Voorhies, Barbara 1976-1985 (Box 5)
    - W 1969-1979 (Box 5)
    - W 1980-1989 (Box 5)
    - Weeks, Dorothy 1972-1974 (Box 5)
    - Wenke, Robert 1972-1978 (Box 5)
    - Whalen, Michael 1971-1977 (Box 5)
    - Whittaker, Thomas W. 1973-1981 (Box 5)
    - Willey, Gordon R. 1972-1979 (Box 5)
    - Wilson, David 1973-1979 (Box 5)
    - Wilson, David 1980-1989 (Box 5)
    - Wolf, Eric R. 1970-1975 (Box 5)
    - World Archaeological Congress 1985-1986 (Box 5)
    - Wright, Henry T. 1966-1975 (Box 5)
    - Y 1978-1989 (Box 5)
    - Z 1969-1984 (Box 5)
  - 1990-2005
    The subseries Correspondence, 1990-2005 (5.75 linear feet) was a separately maintained file which extends and continues the earlier subseries of correspondence covering 1966-1990. The content of this alphabetically arranged subseries was received from the Museum of Anthropology. It includes Parsons' correspondence for a period of approximately 15 years. Materials reflect his multi-faceted professional life during the years he directed the Program in Latin American and Caribbean Studies, was Visiting Professor in Argentina and Bolivia, taught as professor of anthropology, and was Curator of Latin American Archaeology in the Museum of Anthropology.
    The subseries documents Parsons' work with professional associations, his teaching work in universities in Argentina and Bolivia and his field research in Mexico, Argentina, Egypt, Australia, Italy and Mongolia. There is extensive correspondence with national and international colleagues and contacts, including many of the correspondents named in the first series, as well as John Clark, Andrew Darling, Paul Durrenburger, Susan Evans, Suzanne Fish, Frances Hayashida, Mary Hodge, William Honeychurch, William Isbell, Richard Lesure, Charles Kolb, Ramiro Matos, Leah Minc, Hellen Pollard, Dean Snow, Charles Stanish and Eric Wolf.
    - Abdi, Kamyar 2000-2002 (Box 5)
    - Adams, Charles 1993-1996 (Box 5)
    - Adler, Mike 1987 (Box 5)
    - Albarracin, Juan 1995-1997 (Box 5)
    - Albeck, María 1993-1997 (Box 5)
    - Alconini, Sonia 1999-2000 (Box 5)
    - Alden, John R. 1992-1993 (Box 5)
    - Aldenderfer, Mark 1992-2000 (Box 5)
    - Alcock, Sue and J. Cherry 1993-2001 (Box 5)
    - American Anthropologist 1999-2002 (Box 5)
    - American Antiquity 1986-1999 (Box 5)
    - American Ethnologist 1990 (Box 5)
    - American School of Classical Studies (Athens) 1999 (Box 5)
    - Anawalt, Patricia 1990-1991 (Box 5)
    - Anaya, Edgar 2002 (Box 5)
    - Ancient Mesoamerica 1990-2002 (Box 5)
    - Andrews, Anthony 1994-2002 (Box 5)
    - Angelo, Dante 1996-2001 (Box 5)
    - Anschuetz, Kurt 1990-2001 (Box 5)
    - Anthropology, Museum of 1989-2004 (Box 5)
    - Antiquity 1998-2003 (Box 5)
    - Arellano, Carmen 1994-2002 (Box 5)
    - Argentina-Miscellaneous 1992-2000 (Box 6)
    - Arizona, University Press 2002 (Box 6)
    - Arqueología Mexicana 2002-2004 (Box 6)
    - Ashmore, Wendy 1993-1994 (Box 6)
    - Attema, Peter 2002-2004 (Box 6)
    - Australian Research Council 1997-1999 (Box 6)
    - Balossi, Francesca 1999-2000 (Box 6)
    - Baños, Eneida 1990 (Box 6)
    - Barba, Luis 1990-1991 (Box 6)
    - Barbour, Warren 2001 (Box 6)
    - Barker, Alex 1990-1998 (Box 6)
    - Barker, Graeme 1998-2000 (Box 6)
    - Barnes, Gina 1998 (Box 6)
    - Barrera, Alejandro José (Chu) 1997-2005 (Box 6)
    - Barreto, Cristiana 1997 (Box 6)
    - Bastien, Joseph 1991-1994 (Box 6)
    - Bauer, Brian 1990-2001 (Box 6)
    - Bawden, Garth 1986-1991 (Box 6)
    - BBC 1997-1998 (Box 6)
    - Becker, Marshall 1994 (Box 6)
    - Beekman, Chris 1994-2001 (Box 6)
    - Bell, Karen 1991 (Box 6)
    - Berman, Marc 1990-1998 (Box 6)
    - Bernard, Russell 1993 (Box 6)
    - Berres, Thomas 1999 (Box 6)
    - Bettarel, Robert 1995 (Box 6)
    - Bey, George 1990 (Box 6)
    - Blackwell, Publishers 2000 (Box 6)
    - Blake, Michael 1991 (Box 6)
    - Blanton, Richard 1990-2001 (Box 6)
    - Blitzer, Harriet 1990 (Box 6)
    - Bolivia 1999-2000 (Box 6)
    - Bonevich, Jeffrey 1991-1995 (Box 6)
    - Bonnier, Elisabeth 2002 (Box 6)
    - Borejsza, Aleksander 1998-1999 (Box 6)
    - Bradley, Richard 1993-1994 (Box 6)
    - Bray, Tamara 1995-1998 (Box 6)
    - Bray, Warwick 1993-1998 (Box 6)
    - Brigham Young University 2000 (Box 6)
    - Bronson, Bennet 1986-1997 (Box 6)
    - Browman, David 1992-2000 (Box 6)
    - Brown, David 1997-2000 (Box 6)
    - Brubacker, Robert 1993-2003 (Box 6)
    - Brumfiel, Elizabeth 1993-2003 (Box 6)
    - Buliabasich, Catalina 1993-1998 (Box 6)
    - Bunster, Cora 1994 (Box 6)
    - Burger, Richard 1990 (Box 6)
    - Bustos Thames, Horacio 1996-1998 (Box 6)
    - Butzer, Karl 1993 (Box 6)
    - Bye, Robert undated (Box 6)
    - Campagno, Marcelo 1995 (Box 6)
    - Canger, Una 1993-1995 (Box 6)
    - Capriles, Jose 1999-2003 (Box 6)
    - Careaga, Jose and Acela 1990-1997 (Box 6)
    - Carrasco, David 2000 (Box 6)
    - Carrasco, Pedro 1990 (Box 6)
    - Catamarca, Universidad Nacional de 1996-1997 (Box 6)
    - Ceruti, María Constanza undated (Box 6)
    - Chalco-Miscellaneous undated (Box 6)
    - Champio, Tim 1990-1994 (Box 6)
    - Charlton, Thomas 1990-2001 (Box 6)
    - Chartkoff, Joseph 1987 (Box 6)
    - Chavez, Karen and Sergio 1992-2004 (Box 6)